A Finding Aid to the Peter Blume Papers, 1870-2001, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Correspondence, 1926-1992; Series 2; Archival Resource Key; 1.8 Linear feet Box 1-3
  - Wachs, Ethel and Paul, 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 98)
  - Wadsworth Atheneum, 1954-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 99)
  - Walsh, Alexander DeWitt, 1980-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 100)
  - Walter, Eda Loux, circa 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 101)
  - Warren, Robert, Eleanor, Rosanna, and Gabriel, 1959-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 102-103)
  - Washington Art Association, 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 104)
  - Wenner-Gren Foundation for Anthropological Research, 1953-1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 105)
  - Westcott, Glennary, 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 106)
  - Weston, Christine, 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 107)
  - White, E.B., 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 108)
  - Whitney, Betsey, 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 109)
  - Whitney, Tom, Julia and Marguerite, 1965-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 110)
  - Whitney Museum of American Art, 1951-1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 111)
  - Wilbur, Charlee and Richard, circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 112)
  - Worcester Art Museum, 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 113)
  - W, 1970-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 114)
  - Yale University, 1952-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 115)
  - Fragments and First Names Only, 1947-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 116)
  - Letters from Peter Blume, Archival Resource Key (Box 2)
    - Blankenhorn, Heber, 1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 117)
    - Blume, Grace, 1934; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 118)
    - Blume, Grace, 1955-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 119)
    - Blume, Grace, 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 120)
    - Blume, Grace, circa 1930s-circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 121)
    - Blume, Rose, 1944-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 122)
  - Letters from Grace Blume, Archival Resource Key (Box 2)
    - Blume, Peter, circa 1925-1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 123)
    - Blume, Peter, 1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 124)
    - Blume, Peter, 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 125)
    - Blankenhorn, Ann and Heber, 1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 126)
    - Blankenhorn, Ann and Heber, 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 127)
    - Blankenhorn, Ann and Heber, 1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 128)
    - Blankenhorn, Ann and Heber, 1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 129)
    - Blankenhorn, Ann and Heber, 1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 130)
    - Blankenhorn, Ann and Heber, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 131)
    - Blankenhorn, Ann and Heber, 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 132)
    - Craton, Marshall, 1954-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 133)
    - Holsten, Edward and Mrs., 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 134)
    - Holsten, Edward and Mrs., 1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 135)
  - Letters from Grace Blume, Archival Resource Key (Box 3)
    - Holsten, Edward and Mrs., 1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Condolence Letters, 1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Margaret Larkin to Ann Blankenhorn, 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Writings and Notes, 1929-1986; Series 3; Archival Resource Key; 0.5 Linear feet Box 3, 9
  Writings by Blume include a travel journal, a notebook, lists of works of art, lectures, talks, and other writings about his art, about other artists and friends, and about art in general. Writings by others include theses and scholarly papers on Blume and poetry. Also found is a selection of criticism on The Rock, written by school children.
  - Travel Journal, by Peter Blume, 1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 4)
    from South Pacific cruise
  - Notebook, circa 1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 5)
    on Arshille Gorky's suicide
  - On Picasso's Guernica, by Peter Blume, Talk at Valentine Gallery, circa 1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 6)
    Includes printed materials
  - "The Artists Responsibility as a Citizen," by Peter Blume, Lecture from The Arts, Sciences and Professions in the Post-War World Conference, circa 1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - "Modern Artists on Artists of the Past," by Peter Blume, Lecture for Conference at Musuem of Modern Art, 1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Statement on the Trial of 11 Communists, by Peter Blume, circa 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - "A Tribute to Charles Burchfield," by Peter Blume, 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - On Louis Bouche, by Peter Blume, Talk from American Academy in Rome Annual Meeting of Board of Trustees, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - "Julian Levy," by Peter Blume, circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - On His Art, by Peter Blume, circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - On Rueben Nakian, by Peter Blume, Speech for Medal Ceremony of American Academy of Arts and Letters, circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - On Recollection of the Flood, by Peter Blume, circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - On Alexander Calder, by Peter Blume, Speech from Presenting A.C. Gold Medal for Sculpture, circa 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - "Ivan Lorraine Albright," by Peter Blume, circa 1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - On Hart Crane, by Peter Blume, 1929; circa 1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 18)
    Also includes "The Bridge," by Hart Crane
  - Notes for Unidentified Lectures and Talks, circa 1960-circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Lists of Works of Art, circa 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 20)
    Oversized material housed in Box 9, F2
  - "Peter Blume," by Robert Ulrich Godsoe, Mock-Up Biography, circa 1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - "Third Declamation," by Kenneth Burke, circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Forward, by John Driscoll, for Metamorphosis Catalog, Ditenfass Gallery, circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - "Grandma Moses and Peter Blume," by Eloise Barrangon, Poem, circa 1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - "The World," by Wade Van Done, Poem, circa 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Poetry, by Heber Blankenhorn, circa 1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - "Peter Blume," by Frank Getlein, 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - "The Life and Works of Peter Blume," by George John Seidel, College of Wooster, 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Poetry, by Nancy Cardozo, circa 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Speech, by Gordon Hendricks, 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Children's Criticism, on "The Rock", 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - "Peter Blume's Ventriloquist Act," by Mark R. Kriss, 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - "Peter Blume's Paintings of the 1930's [sic]," by Barbara D. Gallati, Thesis, 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - "The Rock by Peter Blume" by Michael A. Kelly, 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - "Peter Blume--Sixty Years of His Art (1926-1986)," by Frank Anderson Trapp with Forward by Malcolm Cowley, circa 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Oversized Lists of Works of Art, scanned with Box 3, F20, circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Subject Files, circa 1930-1988; Series 4; Archival Resource Key; 0.5 Linear feet Box 3-4
  Subject files were originally maintained by Peter Blume regarding organizations, works of art, exhibitions, reference files, and about Blume's brother-in-law, Heber Blankenhorn. Files include a variety of materials, such as correspondence, administrative records, writings, printed material, and photographs. Reference files contains photographs and clippings of works of art used as inspiration by Blume.
  - American Academy of Arts and Letters, Archival Resource Key (Box 3)
    - Correspondence, Copies, 1973-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Meeting Minutes, 1973-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Meeting Minutes, 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Reports, 1974-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Treasurer's Reports, 1973-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Statement of Income, 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - American Artists Congress, 1930s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 42)
    Includes correspondence, writings, printed material, and administrative records
  - Autumn Silkscreen, 1987-1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 43)
    Includes a proposal, correspondence, and legal records
  - The Crucifixation, 1954-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 44)
    Includes correspondence and printed material
  - Blankenhorn, Heber, 1931-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 45)
    Includes material concerning Blankenhorn's donation of his personal papers and military career, and printed materials.
  - "Chicago Show" (1976)--Museum of Contemporary Art, 1975-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 46)
    Includes correspondence, printed material, photographs, and lists of works of art
  - Connecticut Council on the Arts, 1979-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 47)
    Includes writings, photographs, and printed material
  - Eternal City, 1937-1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 48-49)
  - Tasso's Oak, 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 50)
    Includes correspondence, photographs, and printed material
  - Reference Files, circa 1930-circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 51-55)
  - The Rock, 1948-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
    Includes clippings and material regarding the Carnegie Prize. Oversized material housed in Box 9, F4.
  - Oversized The Rock Clippings, scanned with Box 4, F1-2, 1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Personal Business and Financial Records, 1934-1983; Series 5; Archival Resource Key; 0.6 Linear feet Box 4, 9
  Found here are records relating to the sale, exhibition, and loan of Peter Blume's works of art. Also found are financial records relating to the construction of Blume's home.
  - Business Correspondence, Archival Resource Key (Box 4)
    - The Boat, 1936-1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Coe Kerr Gallery, 1976-1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Currier Gallery of Art, 1963-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Ditenfass Gallery, 1973-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 6-7)
    - Durlacher Bros., 1941-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 8-10)
    - Julian Levy Gallery, 1938-1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Kennedy Galleries, 1967-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Kay Sage Tanguy Estate, 1963-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Museum of Modern Art, 1934-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Public Works of Art Project and Public Buildings Administration, 1934-1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - The Rock, 1952-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 16)
      Regarding conservation and restoration
    - WPA, Cannonsburg, Pennsylvania Post Office, 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Consignment Receipts and Lists, 1963-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Sales Receipts, 1970-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Gift Receipts, 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Invoice, 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Price Lists, circa 1960-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 22-23)
  - Mailing List, circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Legal Records, 1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Condition Reports, 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Tax Correspondence, 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Household and Building Records and Invoices, 1958-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 28-30)
    Oversized material housed in Box 9, F3
  - Oversized Household and Building Records, scanned with Box 4, F28-30, 1958-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Printed Material, 1930-1990; Series 6; Archival Resource Key; 0.7 Linear feet Box 4-5, 9, OV 15-16
  This series has been partially scanned. In some cases, only relevant pages of printed materials have been scanned.
  Printed materials concern Peter Blume's career, exhibitions, artwork, and art in general. Exhibition announcements and catalogs are found for Peter Blume's solo and group shows, some of which are annotated by Blume. Also found are posters, one of which includes a poem by Malcolm Cowley entitled Urn that is illustrated by Blume.
  - Auction Catalog, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Bulletins, 1934; 1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 32-33)
  - Clippings, 1930-1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 34-36)
  - Clippings, 1940-1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Clippings, 1950-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Clippings, 1960-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Clippings, 1970-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Clippings, 1980-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Clippings, 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Clippings, circa 1930-circa 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Clippings, Concerning Friends, 1938-circa 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Congressional Record, Communist Activities in Museums, 1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Exhibition Announcements, 1964-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1940-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 47-49)
    Oversized material housed in Box 9, F5
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 50)
    Annotated
  - Magazines, 1924-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 51-54)
  - Magazines, 1961-1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 1-5)
  - Reproductions of Works of Art, circa 1940; circa 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 6-7)
    Oversized material housed in Box 9, F1
  - Horizon, 1961 July; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Oversized Reproductions of Works of Art, scanned with Box 5, F6-7, circa 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Oversized Exhibition Catalog, scanned with Box 4, F47-49, 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Posters, 1950s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box OV 15, Folder 1)
  - Posters, 1950s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box OV 16, Folder 1)
- Scrapbooks, 1934-1942; Series 7; Archival Resource Key; 3 Folders Box 5
  Found is a clippings scrapbook dating from 1934 to 1939 and a fragment of a scrapbook from 1942 to 1944. The clippings scrapbook contains articles, most of which discuss Blume's works of art South of Scranton and The Eternal City. The scrapbook fragment contains a clipping, a postcard, a telegram from Ebie Blume to Mrs. Heber Blankenhorn, a diary entry, and a ledger page concerning the running of a household.
  - Scrapbook 1, 1934-1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 9-10)
  - Scrapbook 2, Fragment, 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 11)
    Includes a clipping, telegram, diary, and page of a ledger
- Photographs, 1917-circa 1980; Series 8; Archival Resource Key; 1.1 Linear feet Box 5-6, 9
  Found are portraits and snapshots of Peter Blume, Grace 'Ebie' Blume, family members, friends, and colleagues. Other photographs depict travel, parties, exhibitions, the outdoors, homes, pets, and of works of art including paintings and sculpture.
  Photographs of Peter Blume depict Blume painting outdoors and in his studio, with his art, with Grace Blume, and with family and friends. Travel photos are from Europe, Japan, and the American West. Some of the travel photos are of Ned and Nancy Holsten, the Blumes' travel companions and friends. Photographs of friends and family include the Cowleys, the Blankenhorns, the Askews, the Josephsons, and the Sobys, among others.
  Photographs from a terrace party, likely taken by H. Strauss, depict many of the Blumes' friends and family in addition to Arthur Miller.
  Photographs of exhibitions are from the American Institute in Rome and the Carnegie Institute.
  - Photo Album, 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 12)
    Harry Blume's Birthday
  - Peter Blume, Portraits, circa 1930-circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Peter Blume, Painting in Studio, 1944-circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Peter Blume, Painting Outside, circa 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Peter Blume, in Studio, circa 1950-circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Peter Blume, With Art, circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Peter Blume, Snapshots, circa 1925-circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 18)
    Oversized material housed in Box 9, F8
  - Grace "Ebie" Blume, circa 1920-circa 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Peter and Grace Blume, circa 1930-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Peter and Family, circa 1935-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Peter, Grace, and Friends, Archival Resource Key (Box 5)
    - Snapshots, circa 1920-circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Trip to Woodlawn Plantation, circa 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - With Blankenhorns, circa 1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - With Cowleys, 1945-circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Medal Presentation Ceremony, circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Group Portrait, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 27)
    With Alfred Eisenstaedt, Raphael Soyer, Malcolm Cowley, Barbara Tuchman, and Peter Blume
  - Peter Blume with Georgia O'Keeffe, circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Terrace and Pool Parties, circa 1950-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 29-30)
    With Arthur Miller, Askews, Sobys, Josephsons, and Cowleys
  - Travel, Archival Resource Key (Box 5)
    - Europe and Japan, circa 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - With Ned and Nancy Holsten, circa 1940s-1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 32-33)
    - American West, circa 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Cowley Family, circa 1930-circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Ann and Heber Blankenhorn, 1935-1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Friends and Family, 1917-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 37)
    Mostly unidentified. Oversized material housed in Box 9, F9.
  - Pets and Animals, circa 1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Blume's Home, Gardens, and Construction, circa 1930s-1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Homes, Others, circa 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Outdoors, Landscapes, circa 1940-circa 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Exhibition, Carnegie and Others, 1982; 1934-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Exhibition, American Academy in Rome, Venus (1974), circa 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Contact Sheets, circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Works of Art, Packets, circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 45-49)
  - Works of Art, Sculpture, circa 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 50)
    Oversized material housed in Box 9, F7
  - Works of Art, Studies, circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Works of Art, Drawings, circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Works of Art, Painting, circa 1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Works of Art, Painting, 1950s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Transparencies, 1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Slides, circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Xeroxes of Photos of Works of Art, circa 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Oversized Photos of Works of Art, Sculpture, scanned with Box 5, F50, circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Oversized Peter Blume, Snapshot, scanned with Box 5, F18, circa 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Oversized Friends and Family Photos, scanned with Box 5, F37, circa 1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Artwork, 1932-1984; Series 9; Archival Resource Key; 2 Linear feet Box 6-9, OV 10-14
  Works of art by Blume include sketches, preliminary drawings, prints, and one final drawing. Media include pencil, pen, pastel, and charcoal. Sketches entitled Doodles were likely numbered and identified by Blume. Also found are a series of drawings of heads, some of which are mounted. Studies for Blume's works include: Parade (1930), The Obelisk (1932), Harps (1932), Fracture Ward (1945), The Rock (1948), The Shrine (1950), The Crucifixion (1951), Castle of Euralyus (1952), Landscape in Bali (1954), The Passage to Aetna (1956), Hadrian's Villa (1958), Tasso's Oak (1960), Banyon Trees (1961), Winter (1964), Summer (1966), Satyr with Cock (1967), Recollection of the Flood (1969), Boulders of Avila (1976), From the Metamorphosis (1979), Crashing Surf (1982), and Autumn (1984).
  Works by Peter Blume owned by the Craton family are also found. These include three prints, one entitled Harps, and one drawing entitled New England Snow, which was exhibited at the Whitney Museum of American Art in 1938.
  Also found is a work by Deborah Nourse Lattimore entitled Gilt Venus.
  - Designs for a Stand, circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Doodles, DDOND 12-17, circa 1940s-circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Doodles, DDOND 18-25, circa 1940s-circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Doodles, DDOND 26-31, circa 1940s-circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Doodles, DDOND 32-50, circa 1940s-circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Doodles, DDOND 51-65, circa 1940s-circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Doodles, DDOND 66-89, circa 1940-circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Doodles, DDOND 90-99, circa 1940s-circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Doodles, DDOND 100-113, circa 1940s-circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Doodles, DDOND 114-135, circa 1940s-circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Doodles, DDOND 136-154, circa 1940s-circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Doodles, DDOND 155-179 (174 missing), circa 1940s-circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Doodles, DDOND 180-197, circa 1940s-circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Doodles, DDOND 198-203, circa 1940-circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Doodles, DDOND 204-209 (and others), circa 1940s-circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Doodles, DDOND 210-213, circa 1940s-circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Sketches, 1944-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 21-23)
  - Sketches, Heads, 1948-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 24-28)
    Oversized material housed in Box 9, F6
  - Gilt Venus, by Deborah Nourse Lattimore, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 29)
    Oversized material housed in Box 9, F10